Srik(Srikanth) Gorthy

**Linkedin:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/srikgorthy/

Github: https://github.com/sRikg Address: 627 Library Pl, Evanston, IL 60201

## Summary

9+ years experience in Machine Learning and Data Sciences building end-to-end solutions. 4+ years experience as Entrepreneur, solutions architect and team builder from ideation to market launch. Experienced working in various industries such as Music, Banking, Semiconductors, FMCG and Internet Technologies.

#### EDUCATION

# Northwestern University, IL, USA

MS in Artificial Intelligence; GPA: 4.00\*

Sep 2021 - Dec 2022\*

Email: srikgorthy@gmail.com

**Mobile**: +1-773-807-9898

# Indian Institute of Management, Bangalore, India

Certificate, Business Analytics and Intelligence

Jul 2017 - Jun 2018

# Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani, India

BE(Honors) in Chemical

Jan 2009 - Dec 2012

#### EXPERTISE

• Skills: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Data Science, Natural Language Processing, Algorithms and Optimization, Recommender Systems, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning, Human Computer Interaction, Computer Vision

- Tools
  - ML/DL: Python, pytorch, tensorflow, scikit-learn, keras
  - o Data Science: R, RStudio, NLTK, SQL, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, D3.js
  - o Databases: SQL [MySQL, SQL Server, PostgreSQL], AWS [Redshift, RDS]
  - Web Development: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Django, RShiny, Plumber
  - o Other: AWS [EC2, S3, ECS], Google Colab, KNIME, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Git, Docker

#### Publications

- Co-Authored a paper titled "Automated Intelligent Test Planning using Deep Learning Techniques" for the Global AMD Technical Authors Conference in November '21
- Co-Authored a paper titled "Machine Learning-Based Failure Analysis for Verification and Validation" in the Global AMD Technical Authors Conference in November '20

#### EXPERIENCE

## JP Morgan Chase, TX, USA

• AI/Data Science Summer Associate

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

Automated the calculation of various calculation for a 3 Trillion Commercial Portfolio

- $\circ$  Built a end-to-end proof-of-concept automation for loss change explain process for a multi-trillion dollar portfolio reducing calculation time from  $\sim 8$  hours to < 10 seconds
- Replicated multiple calculations with 99+% confidence using explainable ML Models

## AMD, Advanced Micro Devices, Hyderabad, India

• Member Of Technical Staff, ML/AI Engineer

Jan 2020 - Aug 2021

Drove innovation in driver integration validation team, creating automation using ML/AI models

- Developed an Neural Network(NN) model to yield test plans for given driver code changes automating and standardizing existing complex processes saving 1+ hours/day
- Produced multiple NN models tailored to specific areas to identify root cause of a given driver failure saving 5+ FTE resources in a quarter
- $\circ$  Created an ensemble of NN and Naïve Bayes models to identify bug severity reducing manual evaluations by 30% in a quarter

# TVAlly, Hyderabad, India

• CEO and Co-founder

Jul 2017 - Dec 2019

Founded an online music streaming platform for independent music in India with 2000+ users

- Developed a content-based recommender system from scratch; scraped 10000+ songs/tracks; automated track elements annotations; crafted 100+ playlists, decreased search time by 75% and increasing activity rate by 50%
- $\circ\,$  Produced multiple dashboards for executive meetings show casing various KPIs reducing time spent on generating adhoc reports by 90%
- Built and led data science team of four helping build models estimating ideal web page journeys, estimating customer life lengths and aiding marketing efforts

# Google, Hyderabad, India

• Analyst - Trust and Safety, Google Search

Aug 2015 - Jul 2017

Led efforts to reduce spam and abuse in the Trust and Safety team building scalable solutions

- Identified opportunity and created an in-house ML team from scratch to yield scalable solutions; Managed and delivered 5 projects in 2 quarters
- Produced an ensemble model using Linear Discriminant Analysis, Random Forests, and Gradient Boosting Machines to identify gibberish content on an HTML page reducing the spam rate by 35% in a quarter
- $\circ$  Built a tool for auto-segregating user feedback into actionable segments across various teams using NLP techniques alongside K-Means and Gaussian Mixture Models reducing the time to action by 20% and improving feedback response rate by 50%
- o Trained 150+ employees across locations on ML techniques to increase ML adoption

# LatentView Analytics, Chennai, India

• Senior Analyst

Oct 2014 - Jul 2015

Created solutions for client projects in roles assuming responsibility

- Identified causal factors to enhance an album's ranking on the Billboard Charts utilizing PCA for a multinational music conglomerate leading a team of 2
- Crafted strategy to convert prepaid to postpaid accounts using clustering techniques for an Indonesian telephone services provider working onsite improving monthly conversions from 3.5% to 15% in 2 quarters

Analyst Dec 2012 - Sep 2014

Worked on building predictive model solutions for various domains

- $\circ$  Trained 2500 models for various segments of 2 billion rows dataset with 2500 dimensions to detect credit card frauds for a global credit card company aiding fraud prevention by 40%
- Modeled a credit scoring system for a Middle Eastern County's Credit Bureau with an AUC of 0.75. Presented it
  onsite to clients and provided UAT
- Prepared brand perceptual charts by scraping Twitter data through Correspondence Analysis for a multinational beverage brand to identify potential market gaps
- Prepared material and on-boarded 200+ new employees on ML

# Talks & Sessions

- "Natural Language Processing" at Geekle's Python for ML and AI Summit 2021 in April '21
- "A perspective on Artificial Intelligence" at University of Madras, Chennai in January '21
- "Natural Language Processing" at JNTU, Hyderabad in November '20

## AWARDS & RECOGNITION

- Was awarded "Spot bonus" and 7 "Peer Bonus" awards for excellence of delivery and collaborative work at Google
- Was awarded "Encore Award" for diligence and on-time delivery at LatentView in 2014